Preliminary Inventory to the Russia. Legatsiia (Hesse, Germany) Records, 1857-1913
Hoover Institution Archives
Russia. Legatsiia (Hesse, Germany) Records,
1857-1913
29007
Russia. Legatsiia (Hesse, Germany)
17 manuscript boxes (6.8 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Correspondence, reports, circulars, instructions, telegrams, and printed matter, relating to Russian-German relations
Administrative Information
Access
Collection open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Materials were acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1929
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Access Points
Germany; Germany--Foreign relations--Russia; Hesse (Germany); Russia; Russia--Foreign relations--Germany
CONTAINER LIST
- Journey of their Majesties Emperor Alexander II and Consort, 1857 (Box 1)
- Correspondence with the Duke of Nassau concerning the dowry of the late Grand Duchess Elizaveta Mikhailovna, 1857-1862
- Journey of their Majesties Emperor Alexander II and Consort, 1864-65
- Journey abroad of Emperor Alexander II accompanied by Grand Duke Vladimir Aleksandrovich, 1867
- Journeys of Emperor Alexander II
  - 1868-69
  - 1870-71
  - 1873-74
  - 1875-76 (Box 2)
- Telegrams on the war with Japan, 1904
- Journey of Emperor Nicholas II and the Imperial Family, 1896
- Minister-Resident Baron Knorring in Darmstadt and Koburg, 1909
- Confidential correspondence between the St. Petersburg Foreign Office and the Russian Representatives Abroad
  - Lieutenant-Governor of the Caucasus, Tiflis, 1911-13
  - General Shatilov, Kodjor, July-August 1912
  - Governor-General of Samarkand, Tashkent, 1911-12
  - Governor-General of Irkutsk, 1912-13
  - Governor-General of the Amur District. Khabarovsk, 1911-13
- Circulars and instructions of the Foreign Office to Russian Representatives Abroad
  - 1911
  - 1912
  - 1913
- Correspondence with Russian Representatives in: (Box 3)
  - Germany
    - Embassy in Berlin
      - 1911
      - 1912
      - 1913
    - Legation in Munich, 1911-13
    - Legation at Stuttgart, 1911-13
    - Legation at Dresden, 1911
    - Legation at Darmstadt, 1912-13
    - Legation at Hamburg, 1911-12
  - United States, Washington, D.C. Embassy
    - 1911
    - 1912-13
  - Austria-Hungary
    - Embassy in Vienna
      - 1911
      - 1912
      - 1913
    - Consulate General at Budapest, 1911-13
    - Consulate at Prague, 1911-13
    - Consulate at Chernovitz, 1912
    - Consulate at Fiume, 1911
    - Consulate at Saraevo, 1911
  - Spain, Madrid Embassy, 1911-13 (Box 4)
  - Portugal, Lisbon Legation, 1911-13
  - France
    - Embassy in Paris
      - 1911
      - 1912
        - January-June
        - July-October
        - November-December
      - 1913
        - January-July
        - August-December (Box 5)
  - Great Britain
    - Embassy in London
      - 1911
      - 1912
        - January-March
        - April-July
        - August-October
        - November-December
      - 1913 (Box 6)
        - January-July
        - August-November
    - Conusulate General for India, Calcutta, 1910-13
  - Italy, Rome Embassy
    - 1911
    - 1912
    - 1913
  - Japan
    - Embassy in Tokyo
      - 1911
        - January
        - June-December (Box 7)
      - 1912
        - January-June
        - July-December
      - 1913
    - Consulate at Seoul, 1910-12
    - Consulate at Chemulpo, 1911
  - Turkey, Constantinople Embassy
    - 1911
      - January-March
      - April-June
      - July-September (Box 8)
      - October-November
    - 1912
      - January-March
      - April-June
      - July-August
      - September
      - October
      - November-December (Box 9)
    - 1913
      - January-July
      - August-December
  - Balkan Consulates
    - Adrianopol, 1912
    - Bitoli, Serbia, 1912-13
    - Uskub, Serbia, 1911-13
    - Prisrin, Serbia, 1911-13
    - Odrin, Bulgaria, 1913
    - Philippopoli, Bulgaria, 1911-12
    - Varna and Burgas, Bulgaria, 1912-13
    - Saloniki, Greece, 1912-13
    - Mount Athos, 1912-13
    - Skutari, Albania, 1912
  - Asiatic Turkey Consulates
    - Bagdad, 1911-13
    - Bassrah, 1911
    - Bayazet, 1911-12
    - Erzerum, 1911-12
    - Jaffa, 1912
    - Smyrna, 1911-12
    - Van, 1911-12
  - European Legations
    - Belgium, Brussels Legation, 1911-13
    - Denmark, Copenhagen Legation, 1911-13
    - Norway, Christiana Legation, 1911-13
    - Holland, The Hague Legation, 1911-13
    - Sweden, Stockholm Legation, 1911-13
    - Rome, Holy Seat Legation, 1911-13
    - Switzerland, Bern Legation, 1911-13
  - Balkan Peninsula Legations (Box 10)
    - Albania, Valona Commissioner, October-November 1913
    - Bulgaria, Sofia
      - 1911
      - 1912
      - 1913
    - Greece
      - Athens Legation
        - 1911
        - 1912
        - 1913
      - Canea Consulate General (Box 11)
        - 1911
        - 1912-13
    - Montenegro, Cettinie Legation
      - 1911
      - 1912
      - 1913
    - Rumania, Bucharest Legation
      - 1912-13
      - 1913
    - Serbia, Belgrade Legation (Box 12)
      - 1911
      - 1912
      - 1913
  - Central Asia
    - Bukhara Political Agency, 1911
    - Persia
      - Teheran Legation
        - 1911
          - January-April
          - May-August
          - September-October
          - November-December (Box 13)
        - 1912
          - January-February
          - March-April
          - May-August
          - November-December
        - 1913
      - Astrabad Consulate, 1911-12 (Box 14)
      - Ardebil Consulate, 1911-12
      - Ashabad Consulate, 1911-12
      - Astara Consulate, 1911-12
      - Birdjan Consulate, 1912
      - Djulfa Consulate, 1911-12
      - Ispahan Consulate, 1910-11, 1913
      - Kasvin Consulate, 1911-12
      - Kermanshah Consulate, 1911-13
      - Hamadan Consulate, 1912
      - Khoy Consulate, 1912
      - Meshed Consulate, 1911-12
      - Ourmia Consulate, 1910-13
      - Firuz Consulate, 1911
      - Resht (Ghilan) Consulate, 1911-12
      - Seistan Consulate, 1912
      - Tabriz Consulate General, 1911-13
  - Far East
    - China
      - Peking Legation
        - December 1910 - February 1911
        - 1911
          - March-August
          - September-October
          - November-December (Box 15)
        - 1912
          - January-February
          - March-April
          - May-June
          - July-August
          - September-December
        - 1913 (Box 16)
          - January-August
          - September-December
      - Aigun Consulate, 1912
      - Canton Consulate, 1912
      - Shanghai Consulate, 1911-13
      - Ghirin Consulate, 1912
      - Hankow Consulate, 1910-13
      - Hongkong Consulate, 1912
      - Jnkow Consulate, 1912
      - Kashgar Consulate, 1911-12
      - Harbin Consulate, 1911-13
      - Hailar Consulate, 1912
      - Kuanchentzi Consulate, 1911-13
      - Kuldja Consulate, 1911-13
      - Mukden Consulate, 1912-13
      - Urumtzi Consulate, 1911-13
      - Chugutchak Consulate, 1911-13
      - Tientsin Consulate, 1911-12
      - Tsitsikar Consulate, 1911-13
    - Mongolia
      - Consulate General and Diplomatic Agency
        - 1911-March 1912
        - 1912
          - April-September
          - October-December (Box 17)
        - 1913
      - Kobdo and Ouslasautai Consulate, 1911-12
      - Chara Consulate, 1911-13
      - Kosh-Agatch Consulate, 1912
      - Zaisan Consulate, 1911-12
    - Siam, Bangkok Legation, 1910-13
  - Africa
    - Abyssinia, Adis-Ababa Legation, 1910-13
    - Egypt, Cairo Legation, 1911-13
    - Morocco, Tangier Legation, 1911-13
  - Central and South America
    - Argentina, Buenos-Aires Legation, 1910-11
    - Brazil, Rio de Janeiro Legation, 1910-11
    - Mexico, Mexico City Legation, n.d.